DAN KLEIN: We're going to describe now
something called backtracking search.
Backtracking search is the basic
uninformed algorithm for solving CSPs,
and it basically takes two ideas.
The first idea is we should really only
assign one variable at a time.
So on the applet, we didn't
actually see this problem.
But in principle, from the empty
assignment, you've got a whole bunch
of successors.
There's a whole bunch of variables you
could assign next, and for each one,
you have a whole bunch of values
you could assign next.
So the first idea is know at any given
point, there should only be one
variable in play.
And of course, we're going to have to
consider all of its possible values.
So one variable at a time.
The second idea is we should really to
check these constraints as we go.
So for example, when we assign that
second blue value, we should
immediately know we've
done something wrong.
We should be checking our constraints
incrementally as we go.
And one way to say that is we should
only consider assigning values which
do not conflict with previous
assignments.
Now of course, in order to make sure
that the values we're assigning
haven't created a conflict, we might
have to do some computation.
But if you think about this, essentially
what we're doing is we're
doing our goal test incrementally.
In a standard search problem, the
goal test comes at the end.
If you don't pass the goal test, no
worries, maybe your successors will.
Here is CSPs we have
a stronger notion.
We have the notion of passing the goal
test at the end, but we also have the
notion of having screwed up so badly
that even though you've got
successors, they're not
going to work out.
OK, so we need the ability to just
bail as soon as we've violated a
constraint.
And it should be a fairly intuitive
thing to add, but it's not something
you have in search.
In search, the only notion
is the goal test.
Failing the goal test is not bad,
passing the goal test is good.
We need the ability to fail, and really
fail, and get kicked out.
OK, so backtracking search
incorporates two ideas.
The first one is assign one variable at
a time, and the second one is check
the constraints as you go.
Depth first search augmented with
these two ideas is called
backtracking search.
And you might think, why
do they call it that?
Isn't depth first search kind of
already a backtracking search?
Yes, yes.
That's what it's called.
OK.
If you put this stuff together, we
can solve n-queens for something
like n equals 25.
And if we go into our demo, let's take
a look at what this looks like.
So I'm going to change here the
algorithm from naive search to
backtracking.
And again, we start off
with the empty case.
If I click next, I'll assign blue,
and we'll move on to the
next one to the right.
What are we going to assign it?
Well, we're not going to do blue
because that already violates a
constraint.
So we're only going to consider
legal assignments.
And that means we assign red.
And then what do we assign next?
Blue.
Is that a good idea?
I don't know.
That's why we have CSP solvers.
So we keep going.
Red here.
We're smart enough to assign green, but
it's still not going to work out
because here, there won't
be any successors, and
we'll have to backtrack.
But if I click through it, we don't
do a lot of backtracking.
And eventually we just get to the end,
with a couple hiccups along the way.
All right, let's see
this in psuedocode.
So in pseudocode, it would
look something like this.
There would be some function called
backtracking search, and in fact, this
is typically implemented recursively.
So what do you do?
When you recurse, you check to see
whether your assignment is complete.
If so, you return it, because you don't
get a complete assignment unless
everything kind of passed the
constraints along the way.
So the goal test was smeared along the
entire computation to get here.
Then we select a variable, and we
consider each value in its domains in
some order.
And then we do this inner loop that says
if that value doesn't violate a
constraint, extend the partial
assignment in recurse.
OK, so simple enough.
That's backtracking.
It's depth first search, here
implemented recursively, plus this
notion that the variables
come in some order.
Plus this notion that as soon as you
violate a constraint, you fail.
And there are some choice points here.
And the choice points in particular, as
it's written here, are going to be
well, what order should I go
through the variables?
What order should I try to values?
These kinds of ideas are
going to help us make
backtracking search even better.